Every man fights his own war.
The Thin Red Line is a drama, history, war film directed by Terrence Malick.
The story of a group of men, an Army Rifle company called C-for-Charlie, who change, suffer, and ultimately
make essential discoveries about themselves during the fierce World War II battle of Guadalcanal.
It follows their journey, from the surprise of an unopposed landing, through the bloody and
exhausting battles that follow, to the ultimate departure of those who survived.
Pvt. Robert Witt, played by Jim Caviezel.
Lt. Col. Gordon Tall, played by Nick Nolte.
1st Sgt. Edward Welsh, played by Sean Penn.
Pvt. Jack Bell, played by Ben Chaplin.
Capt. James Staros, played by Elias Koteas.
Capt. John Gaff, played by John Cusack.
The Thin Red Line is a 1998 American epic war film
written and directed by Terrence Malick.
It is the second film adaptation of the 1962 novel by
James Jones, following the 1964 film.
Telling a fictionalized version of the Battle of Mount Austen, which was part of the
Guadalcanal campaign in the Pacific Theater of the Second World War, it portrays U.S.
soldiers of C Company, 1st Battalion, 27th Infantry Regiment, 25th Infantry Division,
played by Sean Penn, Jim Caviezel, Nick Nolte, Elias Koteas, and Ben Chaplin.
The novel's title alludes to a line from Rudyard Kipling's poem "Tommy", from Barrack-Room Ballads, in which he says British foot soldiers are
called a "thin red line of [h]eroes", referring to the stand of the 93rd Regiment in the Battle of Balaclava of the Crimean War.
The film marked Malick's return to filmmaking after a 20-year absence.
It co-stars Adrien Brody, George Clooney, John Cusack,
Woody Harrelson, Jared Leto, John C.
Reilly, and John Travolta.
Reportedly, the first assembled cut took seven
months to edit and ran five hours.
By the final cut, footage of performances by Bill Pullman, Lukas Haas, and Mickey Rourke had been removed (one of
Rourke's scenes was included in the special features outtakes of the Criterion Blu-ray and DVD release).
The film was scored by Hans Zimmer and shot by John Toll.
Principal photography took place in Queensland,
Australia and in the Solomon Islands.
20th Century Fox premiered The Thin Red Line in Beverly Hills on December 22, 1998, and released it in a limited release on
December 23, 1998, before a nationwide release on January 15, 1999, and grossed $98 million against a $52 million budget.
Critics gave it a positive reception, praising it for its philosophical depiction of war, Malick's
direction, musical score, cinematography, screenplay, editing, and performances of the cast.
The film was nominated for seven Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted
Screenplay, Best Cinematography, Best Film Editing, Best Original Score, and Best Sound.
It won the Golden Bear at the 1999 Berlin International Film Festival.
Martin Scorsese ranked it as his second-favorite film of the 1990s.
On At the Movies, Gene Siskel called it "the finest
contemporary war film I've seen."
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, steel
helmet, world war ii, battle assignment, invasion.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.